

□ 650-799-3654 | Sahilramani@gmail.com | 🕏 www.sahilramani.com | 🖸 sahilramani | 🛅 sahilramani

Summary_

Experienced graphics programmer and Machine Learning practitioner with 12+ years in the field, including 9 years in video games and 4+ years leading R&D teams. Specializing in the intersection of machine learning and real-time graphics, I focus on creating intuitive software that delivers high quality results. I'm driven to innovate and expand technological boundaries, eagerly embracing new challenges.

Skills

Game Engines Unity3D, Unreal Engine, Godot, several proprietary engines

Graphics HLSL, GLSL, DirectX, OpenGL

Programming Languages & Frameworks C#, C, C++, Python, XAML, C++/Cli, Bash Scripting

Machine Learning NeRF, Object Reconstruction, Gaussian Splatting, Convolutional Neural Networks, Neural Rendering

Version Control Perforce, Git, SVN, Mercurial, Unity Version Control (Plastic SCM)

Work Experience _____

Zoox Inc Foster City, CA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER July 2023 - Present

• Developed 3D Simulation and Synthetic Data generation tools, boosting Zoox model performance by over 20%.

- Engineered frameworks for dataset quality evaluation using ML and statistical approaches, enhancing data integrity.
- Led projects to create realistic simulated worlds, employing state-of-the-art technologies like NeRF, Gaussian Splatting, and related techniques.

Unity Technologies Seattle, WA, USA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER / SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Aug. 2019 - July 2023

- Developed a Unity extension using Neural Rendering to dynamically transform game visuals, featured in the Beta teaser for the future of Unity AI.
- Significantly enhanced **machine learning efficiency** by designing **custom GPU kernels & operations**, which streamlined both training and inference processes, reducing overhead and accelerating performance.
- · Led a team of engineers in pioneering research to leverage machine learning for superior game lighting and rendering.
- Implemented high-performance, **GPU-accelerated tile-stitching** for Unity's terrain system with zero latent allocations.
- Patent 18/144,734: System and Method for Interactive Asynchronous Tile-Based Terrain Generation

Crystal Dynamics Redwood City, CA, USA

ENGINE LEAD / SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Nov 2014 Aug 2019
- Directed R&D efforts at Crystal Dynamics, **leading engine and tool technology advancements** for next-gen games.
- Engineered a groundbreaking graph-based blendshape control system from Maya to game, pivotal for Hulk's transformation in Marvel's Avengers.
- Dramatically increased editor and rendering performance, achieving over 20x and 2x improvements respectively within two years.
- Patent #11189068: Macro-based electronic map editing.

Dreamworks Dedicated Unit

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

SOFTWARE APPLICATIONS ENGINEER, ANIMATION & RIGGING TOOLS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER IN TEST, XBOX GRAPHICS

Mar 2013 - Oct 2014

- Contributed to the R&D team at DreamWorks Animation, developing award-winning animation and rigging tools used in over four animated films.
- Enhanced **cache handling and paging** designs, boosting editor performance by 25%.

Microsoft Corporation

Redmond, WA, USA

July 2011 - Oct 2012

Nokia Research Center

RESEARCH INTERN. MOBILE EXPERIENCES

Santa Monica, CA, USA

May 2010 - July 2010

Yahoo! Software Development India

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER / SYSTEMS ENGINEER

July 2006 - July 2009

Education

Masters of Science in Computer Science, Game Development

Los Angeles, CA, USA

Aug 2009 - May 2011

University of Southern California

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

BMS College of Engineering

Aug 2002 - June 2006